<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
  <id>com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio</id>
  <launchable type="desktop-id">com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio.desktop</launchable>
  <name>Davinci Resolve Studio</name>
  <summary>Professional Editing, Color, Effects and Audio Post!</summary>
  <developer id="com.blackmagicdesign">
    <name>Blackmagic Design</name>
  </developer>
  <url type="homepage">https://www.blackmagicdesign.com/products/davinciresolve</url>
  <url type="help">https://www.blackmagicdesign.com/support/</url>
  <project_license>LicenseRef-proprietary=https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/resolve_license.txt</project_license>
  <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
  <description>
    <p>Hollywood’s most powerful tools for professional editing, color correction, audio post and visual effects!</p>

    <p>DaVinci Resolve Studio 20 is the world’s only solution that combines professional 8K editing, color correction, visual effects and audio post production all in one software tool! You can instantly move between editing, color, effects, and audio with a single click. Whether you’re an individual artist, or part of a large team, it’s easy to see why DaVinci Resolve is the standard for high end post production and finishing on more Hollywood feature films, television shows and commercials than any other software.</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Blackmagic Cloud:</strong> DaVinci Resolve 19 features a whole new way of remote collaboration using cloud based workflows! You can host project libraries using Blackmagic Cloud and collaborate on the same timeline, in real time with multiple users all over the world.</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Professional Editing:</strong> Perfect for both offline editorial and online finishing. You get every editing and trimming tool imaginable, stacked and tabbed timelines, multi cam, closed caption and subtitling tools, on screen annotations, faster project loading, 2D and 3D title templates, and dozens of other new features!</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Cut Page Editing:</strong> Designed for projects with tight deadlines that need to be turned around quickly, the cut page is designed for editing speed. The sync bin and source overwrite tools are the fastest way to edit multi cam programs. You can work faster than ever with dual timelines, source tape and smart editing tools. The cut page has new broadcast replay tools for live multi camera broadcast editing, playout and replay with speed control.</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Advanced Color Correction:</strong> Hollywood’s favorite color corrector keeps getting better! You get advanced HDR primary color grading tools with unlimited secondary corrections, power windows and tracking along with a new AI generated object mask, depth map, fast noise and surface tracker, AI camera gyro stabilization, super scaling, dozens of Resolve FX plugins and more.</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Fusion Visual Effects:</strong> Fusion gives you a true 3D workspace with over 250 tools for creating feature film quality visual effects and stunning motion graphics! Now you import and manipulate USD vfx, can create sophisticated composites, use vector paint, animate titles, add 3D particles, key, rotoscope and more, all inside of DaVinci Resolve 19!</p>

    <p>
      <strong>Fairlight Audio Post:</strong> Fairlight is a full blown digital audio workstation with high performance multi track sample level editing and mixing! You get ADR tools, support for sound libraries, audio and video scrollers for quickly syncing sound, a scrolling timeline, normalization and Fairlight FX plugins including a hum remover, de-esser, reverb and more. DaVinci Resolve Studio 19 also includes support for generating and editing Dolby Atmos® home packages!</p>

    <p>Upgrade from the free to the paid version of DaVinci Resolve Studio 19 and you also get IntelliTrack AI, voice isolation, film look creator, ColorSlice, automatic facial recognition for face refinement tools, temporal and spatial noise reduction, photorealistic optical quality motion effects, lens flare, lens blur, aperture diffraction, film damage or film grain Resolve FX. DaVinci Resolve 19 Studio also includes lens distortion correction, high quality de-interlacing, HDR (High Dynamic Range) grading with Dolby Vision® support, stereoscopic 3D tools, remote rendering, multiuser collaboration with chat and more.</p>
  </description>
  <screenshots>
    <screenshot type="default">
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/screenshots/screenshot1.png</image>
      <caption>Edit: The World’s Fastest Professional Editing Software!</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/screenshots/screenshot2.png</image>
      <caption>Cut: Next Generation Editing</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/screenshots/screenshot3.png</image>
      <caption>Color: Hollywood's Most Advanced Color Corrector</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/screenshots/screenshot4.png</image>
      <caption>Fairlight: Professional Tools for Audio Post</caption>
    </screenshot>
    <screenshot>
      <image>https://raw.githubusercontent.com/flat-software/com.blackmagicdesign.ResolveStudio/1782db747f8dceb6a567a4374c8c5acd1967e091/screenshots/screenshot5.png</image>
      <caption>Fusion: Hollywood's Secret Weapon!</caption>
    </screenshot>
  </screenshots>
  <content_rating type="oars-1.1">
    <content_attribute id="social-chat">moderate</content_attribute>
    <content_attribute id="social-info">moderate</content_attribute>
  </content_rating>
  <requires>
    <control>keyboard</control>
    <control>pointing</control>
    <display_length compare="ge">768</display_length>
  </requires>
  <releases>
    <release version="20.0.1" date="2025-06-30">
      <description>
        <p>The following features have been added or updated.</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Support for Blackmagic RAW SDK 4.6.</li>
          <li>Addressed incorrect media pool clip sorting when added to timeline.</li>
          <li>Addressed voice over issues with multi mono configuration enabled.</li>
          <li>Addressed Music Editor not retaining settings on reload.</li>
          <li>Addressed beat marker display when adjusting Music Editor.</li>
          <li>Audio Assistant no longer applies fade outs at the end of the mix.</li>
          <li>Improved IntelliScript alignment of script and transcribe differences.</li>
          <li>Addressed issue loading linked audio clips in media audio player.</li>
          <li>Addressed occasional speed editor issue adding smooth cut.</li>
          <li>Addressed incorrect subtitle animation when appending words.</li>
          <li>Addressed copied Fusion nodes ignoring process layer settings.</li>
          <li>Addressed refresh issue with object removal when switching comps.</li>
          <li>Addressed multiple OpenColorIO issues in the Fusion viewer.</li>
          <li>OCIO FX now allows filtering of color spaces.</li>
          <li>Improved node cache retention for color changes in other layers.</li>
          <li>Addressed magic mask cache reset in multiple scenarios.</li>
          <li>Addressed incorrect thumbnails for ACES 2.0 timelines.</li>
          <li>Improved handling of packet loss with remote monitoring.</li>
          <li>Addressed issue consolidating BRAW spilled recordings.</li>
          <li>Deleting projects now reliably removes project cache.</li>
          <li>General performance and stability improvements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
    <release version="20.0.0" date="2025-05-27">
      <description>
        <p>The following features have been added or updated.</p>

        <p>
          <strong>Key New Features</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved keyframing with dedicated curve view and timeline drawer.</li>
          <li>Voice over tool with record and monitor options.</li>
          <li>Import Blackmagic Cloud Shared folders to media pool.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliScript creates timelines with a user provided script.</li>
          <li>AI Magic Mask v2 with paint brush.</li>
          <li>AI Dialogue Matcher matches clip tone, level and reverberance.</li>
          <li>AI Audio Assistant automatically creates a finished mix.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliCut removes silences and checkerboards speakers.</li>
          <li>Deep image compositing toolset.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Cut Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Voice over palette with cue, voice tools and teleprompter.</li>
          <li>Ripple trimming of audio now available on secondary tracks.</li>
          <li>Replay multi views now show previously used camera angles.</li>
          <li>Tapping time buttons allows camera buttons to preroll replays.</li>
          <li>Auto resync media bins now supports stills and sequences.</li>
          <li>Live overwrite now supports edit keys and search dial.</li>
          <li>Mouse drag to live overwrite multi source and sync bin.</li>
          <li>Trim with safe edit avoids overwriting adjacent clips.</li>
          <li>Media pool metadata palette allows quick review of selected clips.</li>
          <li>Ability to copy, paste and remove attributes from timeline clips.</li>
          <li>Support for a dynamic trimming mode using JKL controls.</li>
          <li>Full featured audio mixer.</li>
          <li>Mini timeline now includes a context menu.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Edit Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Voice over tool with record and monitor options.</li>
          <li>AI Multicam SmartSwitch for automatic angle switching.</li>
          <li>AI VoiceConvert with built-in and user trainable models.</li>
          <li>Support for source tape.</li>
          <li>Ability to view and edit timelines in the source viewer.</li>
          <li>Multicam creation now supports a reference audio track.</li>
          <li>Opening compound clip from timeline matches playhead position.</li>
          <li>Access timeline settings from timeline tab context menu.</li>
          <li>User preference to wrap around 24h timecode.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Cut and Edit Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Improved keyframing with dedicated curve view and timeline drawer.</li>
          <li>Import Blackmagic Cloud Shared folders to media pool.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliScript creates timelines with a user provided script.</li>
          <li>AI Dialogue Matcher matches clip tone, level and reverberance.</li>
          <li>AI Music Editor automatically edits music to desired length.</li>
          <li>AI animated subtitles highlights or animates spoken words.</li>
          <li>AI SuperScale now includes 3x and 4x enhanced upscaling.</li>
          <li>AI Detect Music Beats displays and allows beat snapping.</li>
          <li>New optimized UI layouts option for vertical videos.</li>
          <li>Custom grid for sorting and organizing of media pool thumbnails.</li>
          <li>Text+ paragraph, line wrapping and bounding tools.</li>
          <li>MultiText tool with layers and easy transform, clip and wrap controls.</li>
          <li>Subtitle tracks now support Fusion templates for styling.</li>
          <li>Selectively sync media originals with proxy only cloud sync.</li>
          <li>Imported PSDs can now be split into individual layers.</li>
          <li>Support for Alert Red viewer background mode.</li>
          <li>Transcription engine now offers extended language support.</li>
          <li>Smooth Cut now supports AI Speed Warp.</li>
          <li>Export audio transcriptions with speaker and timecode.</li>
          <li>Export transcriptions with improved phrase and sentence breaks.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Fusion Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Deep image compositing toolset.</li>
          <li>Multi layer pipelining for OpenEXR, PSD and stereoscopic 3D.</li>
          <li>Vector warping toolset for image patching and cleanup.</li>
          <li>Support for 180 VR.</li>
          <li>3D Scene Dome Light.</li>
          <li>Support for native Cryptomatte workflows.</li>
          <li>View color page grade in media out node.</li>
          <li>Faster GPU based pano map and spherical stabilizer tools.</li>
          <li>Ability to search tool based on effects category.</li>
          <li>User selectable starting frames for compositions.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Color Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>AI Magic Mask v2 with paint brush.</li>
          <li>AI Resolve FX Depth Map v2.</li>
          <li>Chroma Color Warper grading.</li>
          <li>Resolve FX Warper features new spline warp controls.</li>
          <li>Open Color IO supported as Resolve FX.</li>
          <li>New optimized UI layouts option for vertical video.</li>
          <li>Display viewer overlays for remote monitoring.</li>
          <li>Stream and monitor H.265 4:2:2 on supported hardware.</li>
          <li>Support for Samsung Log.</li>
          <li>Support for ACES 2.0.</li>
          <li>Ability to generate HDR light level PDF reports.</li>
          <li>LUTs and colorspaces can now be modified in multi-user projects.</li>
          <li>Node layer controls in the advanced panel.</li>
          <li>Lift, gamma, gain Micro Panel sensitivity improvements.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Fairlight Page</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>AI Audio Assistant automatically creates a finished mix.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliCut to remove silences.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliCut to checkerboard dialogue by speaker.</li>
          <li>AI IntelliCut to generate ADR Cues using transcription speaker info.</li>
          <li>Clip EQ now features 6 bands.</li>
          <li>EQ and Level Matcher processes match tone and clip levels.</li>
          <li>EQ and Gain now also available as Fairlight FX plugins.</li>
          <li>Fairlight Chain FX to create and restore frequently chained plugins.</li>
          <li>Drag header color to move tracks and busses in the timeline.</li>
          <li>Automation now supports per channel mode switching.</li>
          <li>Trim automation now remains active through a mix pass.</li>
          <li>Improved view presets store multiple parameters.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>Codecs</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>Apple ProRes encode support on Windows and Linux.</li>
          <li>Encode MV-HEVC without spatial video metadata.</li>
          <li>MV-HEVC encode support on Nvidia systems.</li>
          <li>Support for side by side stereo 3D media decode.</li>
          <li>Side by side display mode for stereo 3D clips in source viewer.</li>
          <li>Editable spatial video metadata properties in inspector.</li>
          <li>GPU accelerated H.265 4:2:2 encodes on supported Nvidia systems.</li>
          <li>GPU accelerated H.265 4:2:2 decodes on supported Nvidia systems.</li>
          <li>Support for growing TS, MTS and M2TS files as media streams.</li>
          <li>Support interlaced rendering for frame based formats.</li>
          <li>HT JPEG 2000 decode support for EXR.</li>
          <li>Quick Export dialog with custom user preset listings and list view.</li>
          <li>Ability to assign custom icons to user presets in deliver page.</li>
          <li>Support for Sony Burano 2.0.</li>
          <li>Support for RED SDK 8.6.</li>
          <li>Support for audio normalization for Dropbox presets.</li>
          <li>Improved PNG support with HDR and SDR signaling.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
          <strong>General Application</strong>
        </p>
        <ul>
          <li>User definable location for media created in Resolve.</li>
          <li>DCTL encryption option in LUT browser menu.</li>
          <li>DaVinci Remote Monitor supports Intel and AMD GPUs on Windows.</li>
          <li>Scripting API support to link full resolution media.</li>
          <li>Scripting API support to replace media preserving sub clip extents.</li>
          <li>Scripting API support for media pool clip to monitor growing file.</li>
          <li>Extras Download Manager for AI models and more.</li>
          <li>Updated remote monitor client with bitrate display.</li>
          <li>Remote monitor now installs with DaVinci Resolve on macOS.</li>
          <li>User preference for automatic cache management.</li>
          <li>Ability to enable dual screen windows in ultrawide displays.</li>
          <li>Support for OCIO 2.4.2 with ACES 2.0 support.</li>
          <li>Preference to import all clips with multi mono audio configuration.</li>
          <li>Bluetooth connection status popup dialog.</li>
          <li>Ability to filter which fonts are visible in Text+.</li>
          <li>Data burn options for synced audio.</li>
          <li>Support for Nvidia Blackwell GPUs with CUDA 12.8.</li>
          <li>General performance and stability improvements.</li>
        </ul>
      </description>
    </release>
  </releases>
</component>
